Ping Ting Soh

Interaction Designer & Front-end Web Developer

sohpingting@hotmail.com

Summary

I am a strong believer that a useful design can change one's life for the better. With that belief, I constantly strive to create designs with a positive impact for users.

I am a generalist in digital design who does research, analysis, design, facilitating and production works. My specialities are interaction design and front-end web development for responsive web/mobile application. I also have experiences in customer support, digital marketing, online payment and e-commerce.

Skills:

Research & Analysis - Stakeholder interview, competitors research, survey, google analytics, contextual enquiry, personas, use case scenarios, storyboard and user testing.

Design - Workflow diagram, sitemap, wireframe, clickable prototype and mood board, style guide, logo design, UI design, web design, illustration, photography and video editing.

Production - Create working prototype in HTML, CSS, jquery/javascript. Occasionally need to implement the design with MVC .net's razor view or with PHP.

Practices - UX Design, Scrum, Agile, Lean Startup and Lean UX

Prototyping tools - Sketch, Omnigraffle, Adobe CS and Invision.

If you share the same passion and motivation as I do, do drop me an email at hello.sohpingting@gmail.com

Experience

UX/UI Designer at PigeonLab Pte Ltd January 2017 - Present

Pigeonhole Live is a real-time interactive Q&A web app that helps to facilitate conversation between event organisers, speakers and it's audience.

Job Scope:

- Design flow, interaction, wireframe and high-fidelity mockup
- Research and analyse user task and scenario
- Elicit high-level requirement from Product Owner and translate them into new features
- Observe, analyse and gather feedback from the clients or their usage to improve ease of use of the existing product
- Copywriting for interface
- Present designs to stakeholders and incorporate their feedback to current design or future phase
- Work closely with developers to get the feature build
- Manage and analyse product performance metric
- Did QA testing and test case management
- Coordinate releases for new features
- Occasionally does the contextual interview and usability testing
- Occasionally does CSS to customise Pigeonhole Live to follow client's brand guide

Freelance Consultant at LumenLab | MetLife Innovation Centre

April 2016 - December 2016 (9 months)

Works with stakeholders to build websites for products with new business model:

Scope:

- Research
- Design (UI and print)
- Coding (HTML, CSS, Javascript)
- Management Online Community
- Setting up and reporting Web analytics

Sites built:

- http://www.lumenlab.sg/
- http://www.convrse.co/
- https://community.lumenlab.asia/
- http://www.moodyslide.com/
- http://collab.lumenlab.sg/

Product built:

- MoodySlide - Mood tracking mobile app

Growth Hacker at Inspire-Tech

June 2015 - February 2016 (9 months)

Hired as a UX/UI Designer and transited to doing growth hacking due to the company's change in priority.

Job Scope:

- Bring growth to RapidSMS
- Create adoption for RapidSMS App
- Assist operation team in customer retention
- Increase online presences and bring growth digitally

Result:

- Increased online presences and triple the numbers of follower on https://twitter.com/easisms
- Created knowledge-base customer support centre

Business Analyst & Digital Designer at SmoovPay

September 2014 - May 2015 (9 months)

SmoovPay is an online payment gateway processing company. Provides secure, affordable and easiest debit & credit card payment collection online.

Job Scope:

- Facilitate in both product planning, product development and product digital marketing
- Manage the product throughout the product life cycle
- Gather and prioritize product and stakeholder requirements
- Work closely with development team to deliver winning products
- Work with sales, marketing and customer support to ensure revenue and stakeholder satisfaction goals are met
- Ensuring that the product and marketing efforts support the company's overall strategy and goals

Creative Programmer at SmoovPay

June 2012 - September 2014 (2 years 4 months)

SmoovPay is an online payment gateway processing company. Provides secure, affordable and easiest debit & credit card payment collection online.

Job Scope:

- Research, design and development online payment solution features
- Technical Support for Online Payment
- Digital Marketing

Frequent Task:

- Create wire framing and sitemap
- Interaction design
- Create user flow
- Create prototype

- Plan strategic work to achieve marketing and sale objective

Occasional Task:

- User research, competitor research
- Interviewing users
- Analysis Review
- Testing and documentation
- Create graphic and visual
- Content generation and copywriting
- Short film making
- Evangelising
- Minimal project management
- Front-end development
- Setup digital marketing campaign
- Create powerpoint content and project pitching

Web, Flash and Graphic Designer

February 2009 - January 2014 (5 years)

Self-employed to provide graphic and web design service to clients.

Job Duties:

- Look for potential client and work directly with them
- Research and analyze client's users and direct competitors
- Plan and propose SEO solutions and marketing campaign to client
- Conceptualise, design and build websites
- Conceptualise and design logo
- Conceptualise ad design graphic for prints

Interactive Specialist at Smoov

May 2011 - December 2011 (8 months)

Smoov is a highly dynamic company whose core team consists of young and energetic professionals in the digital field. The main focus of Smoov is in mobile application, community and commerce development. Smoov has won numerous awards like Asia Pacific ICT Awards (APICTA), National Infocomm Awards (NIA) and Singapore infocomm Technology Federation (SiTF) over the years.

Job Scope:

- Design mobile app interface
- Conceptualise, plan and propose solutions
- Ran social media campaign

- Test and consolidate user feedback on mobile app
- Work with Business Development Personnel to meet client, pitch work and acquire requirement
- Design icon for mobile app
- Troubleshoot and code for the kiosk to print ticket

Junior Web and Graphic Designer

April 2008 - July 2008 (4 months)

Nota Bene Communications (NBC) is a multi-disciplined agency that is balanced in how it provides services like creative ideas, advertising, website design, website development, graphic design, logo designs and corporate or product branding.

Job Scope:

- Coordinate with client to produce newspapers advertisement
- Design website and graphic using Photoshop, Fireworks and Corel draw
- Build website using PHP, HTML, CSS and JavaScript
- Design and graphic for newspaper ads
- Did Search Engine Optimisation (SEO) for the companies' sub sites to bring traffic to main sites

Part-Time Sales Promoter

December 2005 - February 2008 (2 years 3 months)

Top 10 in Sales

Junior Software Developer (Internship)

March 2007 - May 2007 (3 months)

i-Lotus is one of the most successful and well-known GPS module receiver manufacturers and GPS-related product developers in Asia, encompassing applications area such as Navigation, Timing, and Tracking.

Job Scope:

- Assist in testing and developing of GPS receiver
- Setting up and test communication between GPS hardware, software and google map
- Decipher and plot GPS coordinates from hardware to google map
- Used XML, C# and .NET

Education

Nanyang Technological University

Bachelor of Fine Arts (BFA), Game and Interactive Media Design, 2008 - 2012

Activities and Societies: ASIA! on the move, applied research project with Intel

Nanyang Polytechnic

Diploma in Multimedia & Infocomm Technology, Multimedia & Infocomm Technology, 2005 - 2008

Activities and Societies: Trained for World Skill Competition 2007 - Software Application (MS Office & Photoshop), Volley Ball

Honors and Awards

Distinction for Final Year Semestral Project

Ping Ting Soh

Interaction Designer & Front-end Web Developer

sohpingting@hotmail.com



Contact Ping Ting on LinkedIn